¬
{DDS_ACCEPT_EXTORTION}Barely Accepted
{DDS_ACCEPT_HIGH}Happily Accepted
{DDS_ACCEPT_LOW}Just Accepted
{DDS_ACCEPT_MED}Accepted
{DDS_BALANCE_BALANCED}Balanced
{DDS_BALANCE_DEMANDING}Demanding
{DDS_BALANCE_GENEROUS}Generous
{DDS_BALANCE_VERY_DEMANDING}Very Demanding
{DDS_BALANCE_VERY_GENEROUS}Very Generous
{DDS_COUNTER_CLOSE}Almost Accepted
{DDS_COUNTER_INSULTING}Annoyed
{DDS_COUNTER_OPEN}Appreciative
{DDS_COUNTER_STANDARD}Unconcerned
{DDS_DECLARE_ANNOYED}Annoyed
{DDS_DECLARE_UNCONCERNED}Unconcerned
{DDS_DECLARE_UPSET}Upset
{DDS_DECLINE_HIGH}Firmly Rejected
{DDS_DECLINE_LOW}Just Rejected
{DDS_DECLINE_MED}Rejected
{DDS_NEUTRAL}Undecided
{DDS_NEW_OFFER_BETTER}Pleased
{DDS_NEW_OFFER_NEUTRAL}Neutral
{DDS_NEW_OFFER_WORSE}Annoyed
{DDS_REACTION_DISAPPOINTED}Disappointed
{DDS_REACTION_ELATED}Elated
{DDS_REACTION_NEUTRAL}Neutral
{DDS_REACTION_OFFENDED}Offended
{DDS_REACTION_PLEASED}Pleased
{DDS_RECEIVE_ALLY}Receive Ally
{DDS_RECEIVE_ENEMY}Receive Enemy
{DDS_RECEIVE_NEUTRAL}Receive Neutral
{DDS_REJECT_HIGH}Not Interested
{DDS_REJECT_LOW}Not Interested
{DDS_REJECT_MED}Not Interested
{DDS_WELCOME_ALLY}Welcome Ally
{DDS_WELCOME_ENEMY}Welcome Enemy
{DDS_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}Welcome Neutral
{DRT_ARABIC_ACCEPT_BRIBE}I see you are not afraid to show your appreciation. This is good.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACCEPT_GIFT}A gift is a blessing to the giver, no matter how small it may be. Our thanks to you. 
{DRT_ARABIC_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACCESS}The enemies of My Lord lie beyond your lands, so to honour us with passage through them would be a true blessing to us.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_ARABIC_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_ARABIC_ALLIANCE}Alone we are dangerous, but together in alliance we could be unstoppable.
{DRT_ARABIC_ATTACK}The skill and prowess of your warriors is most impressive, and we would ask that they may help us defeat our most wretched enemy.
{DRT_ARABIC_BRIBE}Your current master does not truly honour your accomplishments, but our Lord recognises your greatness, and wishes to know what it would take for you to serve him instead.
{DRT_ARABIC_CEASEFIRE}It is time for all bloodshed to end. Let us cease our struggles. 
{DRT_ARABIC_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_ARABIC_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_ARABIC_COUNTER_INFO}It is hoped that you will find this information of use.
{DRT_ARABIC_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_ARABIC_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_ACCESS}You may not find the idea of your troops moving freely through our lands offensive or worrisome, but we do.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}My Lord does not agree that he needs to entwine his fate with yours so strongly.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_ATTACK}The Lord fears nobody... However nor is fool enough to strike in a blind rage because another man spoke of war.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}If you truly wanted peace, you would have averted war in the first place. You must be made to pay for your senseless spite before we are done with you.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_DEMAND}We will not bow to your demands.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_GIFT}Why would you seek to bless us with this gift? Without good reason, we cannot accept it.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_NULLIFY}The pledges we make are solemn, and it would require the will of my Lord for them to break... Your master's will has no authority here.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_OFFER}We cannot equal this proposition and must turn it down.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}We are not greedy people, and cannot accept this or we shall be seen as such.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}In all truth, your meagre offer falls short of being acceptable.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}Bowing to you as our rulers is not something we are willing to do... There would be no worth in such a life for us.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_REGION}Have you not seen our willingness to die to defend our lands? To forsake our land for profit would be unforgivable!
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_THREAT}Threats are easily made, and we trust you will find them difficult to carry out.
{DRT_ARABIC_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}Not even continued tributes as you suggest would see us agree to this. 
{DRT_ARABIC_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Your behaviour in the past suggests you sometimes seek a treacherous road to a quick victory, which is what your request of passage looks like to us now.
{DRT_ARABIC_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}The only sensible reason we see you want our warriors to walk your lands is so that you would have them travel to a place you could dispose of them.
{DRT_ARABIC_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Perhaps your pledge is brave and noble, but who is to say you do not simply speak of helping us while it is easy to do so now? 
{DRT_ARABIC_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}We find it to be humorous that you might believe you could defeat us, and more amusing still that you think us naive enough to believe you will honour our payment with peace.
{DRT_ARABIC_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}We are not so foolish as to accept something that you will almost certainly seek to take back from us.
{DRT_ARABIC_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}My Master senses that your promise of ongoing support is merely meant to entice him to agree, and that honouring the deal is not truly on your agenda.
{DRT_ARABIC_FINISHED}.
{DRT_ARABIC_GIFT}My Master seeks to honour you, and hopes that this gift will prove his sincerity.
{DRT_ARABIC_INFO}Let us share our knowledge so that we may both learn of the world together.
{DRT_ARABIC_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}If there is a need to maintain our alliance any longer, then it is a need only you feel.
{DRT_ARABIC_PROTECTORATE}Do not make your people suffer any longer, you can do nothing to us from conquering you. Instead, become a part of our greater destiny.
{DRT_ARABIC_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_ARABIC_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_ARABIC_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_ARABIC_REJECT_BRIBE}You have failed to grasp what kind of man I am. If loyalty is unfamiliar to you, then you ask me to join the poorest of people.
{DRT_ARABIC_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}We have no desire to discuss this with you now at all.
{DRT_ARABIC_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}The talking has gone on and on and on and on, and nothing has been settled. This negotiation is now ended and we are immensely relieved to be done with it all.
{DRT_ARABIC_THREAT}My Lord wishes you to know that unless you honour him with this tribute, that he will ensure that your people do not live to spend the money!
{DRT_ARABIC_TRADE}Trade is a good first step on the road to true trust, and will help both of us profit along that journey.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_BRIBE}Knowing that you would deign to spend such a sum to secure my allegiance is all I need to be sure that you are the right master to serve.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Very well, you can count on our support.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_GIFT}Your well-intentioned gift is welcome, and you have our gratitude.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We look forward to the wedding, and our future together throughout the years.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}I pray that this union between us shall be prosperous.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}We are grateful to be able to count on your support.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACCESS}If you would grant our armies access through your lands, it would benefit our struggle against our enemies.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ALLIANCE}Let our people enter an alliance to strengthen both of our positions. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_ATTACK}Could we ask of your assistance in battle with our enemy?
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_BRIBE}You would find yourself in a position of power and prominence should you accept this invitation to join the our number.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_BUY_VOTE}Perhaps we could call upon your support in the election?
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_CEASEFIRE}Let us stop the bloodshed, and bring open hostilities to an end.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_COUNTER_INFO}Our people would like to share some information with you.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_ACCESS}While you can see the need to march your soldiers through our lands, we do not. Permission must be refused at this time. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}We do not believe an alliance would be in our best interests at this time. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_ATTACK}Attacking these people is not in our best interests, so we must refuse. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}We will not be bartering over this serious moment of ascension.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}My Lord does not share your desperate and cowardly urge to escape battle. Perhaps you now realise that you will lose this struggle?
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_DEMAND}We simply do not see how to attempt to meet these demands.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_GIFT}Our people cannot trust the nature in which this gift is intended.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_NULLIFY}We are not willing to abandon our treaty with these people simply because you would wish it to happen.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}This is too serious a union for us to consider at this moment.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_OFFER}We cannot match this offer, and must decline as a result.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}This is far too generous and we would owe you too much.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}You simply do not offer enough with this.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}Why do you think we have not surrendered yet? Maintaining our freedom is as important as maintaining our very lives.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_REGION}To give up the lands our people died to earn and defend for a pouch of coin simply would not do.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We shall not consider a royal union under any doubt or duress.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}We are not looking to buy your support like this.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_THREAT}Our people has no fear of your threats, which to be honest seem hollow.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}We cannot agree to this, even for a steady supply of coin.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Our people has no desire for your armies to study the lay of our lands.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Though that access could be useful for our people in times of war, we cannot be certain that you wouldn't change your mind once we begin to cross your lands. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Your promise of support is the kind that is easy to make without actually having to honour it.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}We do not believe that you will stay your swords even if we meet your demands.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}Your offer of land seems most generous, but there is enough reason to doubt that you wouldn't seek to take it back from us by one means or another.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}Your people's history is one of broken promises, I do not trust your offer.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}We do not believe that you are capable of honouring such a series of tributes, even if you truly intend to.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_FINISHED}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_GIFT}Accept this gift as an example of our goodwill. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_INFO}We would wish to share our knowledge of the world with you.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}The time for our alliance's demise has come to pass. We shall both seek our own path to glory now. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accept my hand in marriage and unite our people in an alliance to last.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_PROTECTORATE}Why continue to struggle against our superior forces? Become our vassal and we shall lead you to greatness under our rule.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_REJECT_BRIBE}My loyalty is not something that you can put a price on so simply.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}We're simply not interested in discussing such a proposal. 
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}We are not making sufficient progress here to suggest there is any reason to continue... These negotiations are over.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}It is time for us to seal a serious pact through a royal marriage.
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_SELL_VOTE}Perhaps you would want our support in the election?
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_THREAT}We can afford to spare you from our conquests, should of course you be prepared to pay tribute as such...
{DRT_DOLAMROTH_TRADE}It would be quite profitable for both of our peoples to establish trade between us.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_BRIBE}Knowing that you would deign to spend such a sum to secure my allegiance is all I need to be sure that you are the right master to serve.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Very well, you can count on our support.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_GIFT}Your well-intentioned gift is welcome, and you have our gratitude.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We look forward to the wedding, and our future together throughout the years.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}I pray that this union between us shall be prosperous.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}We are grateful to be able to count on your support.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACCESS}If you would grant our armies access through your lands, it would benefit our struggle against our enemies.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_ALLIANCE}Let our people enter an alliance to strengthen both of our positions. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_ATTACK}Could we ask of your assistance in battle with our enemy?
{DRT_ENGLISH_BRIBE}You would find yourself in a position of power and prominence should you accept this invitation to join the our number.
{DRT_ENGLISH_BUY_VOTE}Perhaps we could call upon your support in the election?
{DRT_ENGLISH_CEASEFIRE}Let us stop the bloodshed, and bring open hostilities to an end.
{DRT_ENGLISH_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_COUNTER_INFO}Our people would like to share some information with you.
{DRT_ENGLISH_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_ACCESS}While you can see the need to march your soldiers through our lands, we do not. Permission must be refused at this time. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}We do not believe an alliance would be in our best interests at this time. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_ATTACK}Attacking these people is not in our best interests, so we must refuse. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}We will not be bartering over this serious moment of ascension.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}My Lord does not share your desperate and cowardly urge to escape battle. Perhaps you now realise that you will lose this struggle?
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_DEMAND}We simply do not see how to attempt to meet these demands.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_GIFT}Our people cannot trust the nature in which this gift is intended.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_NULLIFY}We are not willing to abandon our treaty with these people simply because you would wish it to happen.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}This is too serious a union for us to consider at this moment.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_OFFER}We cannot match this offer, and must decline as a result.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}This is far too generous and we would owe you too much.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}You simply do not offer enough with this.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}Why do you think we have not surrendered yet? Maintaining our freedom is as important as maintaining our very lives.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_REGION}To give up the lands our people died to earn and defend for a pouch of coin simply would not do.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We shall not consider a royal union under any doubt or duress.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}We are not looking to buy your support like this.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_THREAT}Our people has no fear of your threats, which to be honest seem hollow.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}We cannot agree to this, even for a steady supply of coin.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Our people has no desire for your armies to study the lay of our lands.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Though that access could be useful for our people in times of war, we cannot be certain that you wouldn't change your mind once we begin to cross your lands. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Your promise of support is the kind that is easy to make without actually having to honour it.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}We do not believe that you will stay your swords even if we meet your demands.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}Your offer of land seems most generous, but there is enough reason to doubt that you wouldn't seek to take it back from us by one means or another.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}Your people's history is one of broken promises, I do not trust your offer.
{DRT_ENGLISH_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}We do not believe that you are capable of honouring such a series of tributes, even if you truly intend to.
{DRT_ENGLISH_FINISHED}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_GIFT}Accept this gift as an example of our goodwill. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_INFO}We would wish to share our knowledge of the world with you.
{DRT_ENGLISH_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}The time for our alliance's demise has come to pass. We shall both seek our own path to glory now. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accept my hand in marriage and unite our people in an alliance to last.
{DRT_ENGLISH_PROTECTORATE}Why continue to struggle against our superior forces? Become our vassal and we shall lead you to greatness under our rule.
{DRT_ENGLISH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_ENGLISH_REJECT_BRIBE}My loyalty is not something that you can put a price on so simply.
{DRT_ENGLISH_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}We're simply not interested in discussing such a proposal. 
{DRT_ENGLISH_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}We are not making sufficient progress here to suggest there is any reason to continue... These negotiations are over.
{DRT_ENGLISH_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}It is time for us to seal a serious pact through a royal marriage.
{DRT_ENGLISH_SELL_VOTE}Perhaps you would want our support in the election?
{DRT_ENGLISH_THREAT}We can afford to spare you from our conquests, should of course you be prepared to pay tribute as such...
{DRT_ENGLISH_TRADE}It would be quite profitable for both of our peoples to establish trade between us.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}I believe I have chosen wisely in pledging my service to the the Great Eye.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Ja, you can count on our support.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}. 
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_GIFT}You clearly mean to honour us, your gift here proves it.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We look forward to the wedding, and our future together throughout the years.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}I pray that this union between us shall be prosperous.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}We are thankful you have the wisdom to support us.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACCESS}Allowing us to march across your lands to attack our foes would be an act of true friendship. 
{DRT_GERMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_GERMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_GERMAN_ALLIANCE}Who could begin to fathom the might of our combined forces and ambitions? We should enter an alliance.
{DRT_GERMAN_ATTACK}Your assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated.
{DRT_GERMAN_BRIBE}My Master shows those who serve it far more respect and honour than your current ruler. Perhaps you should join us?
{DRT_GERMAN_BUY_VOTE}Perhaps we could call upon your support in the election?
{DRT_GERMAN_CEASEFIRE}To continue our conflict now seems pointless, and we would call an end to the bloodshed.
{DRT_GERMAN_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_GERMAN_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_GERMAN_COUNTER_INFO}Perhaps if we shared our information, it would make a difference.
{DRT_GERMAN_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_GERMAN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_ACCESS}While we understand why you wish passage through our lands, this is not something we are ready to accept as yet.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}The Dark Lord does not seek to enter an actual alliance with your people for now.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_ATTACK}We do not have good enough reason to attack these people with you, and must decline.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}No, our vote on the control of Middle-earth is not for sale.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}You may not be able to afford the losses of this war, but we can, and are pleased to know you are close to breaking.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_DEMAND}My Master will not attempt to meet these demands you make.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_GIFT}There is no sense in you giving us this gift, which makes it an offer that we cannot trust.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}We can see no rational excuse to end our alliance now. 
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}This is too serious a union for us to consider at this moment.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_OFFER}Without a means to offer something in return, we must decline. 
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}The Dark Lord has no need of your offerings.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}Frankly, this proposal does not offer us enough.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}The Great Eye has endured too many hardships to believe it will fall before the threat you pose, and will resist any attempt at replacing the Dark Lord as its ruler.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_REGION}You jest?
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We shall not consider a royal union under any doubt or duress.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}We are not looking to buy your support like this.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_THREAT}The Dark Lord Sauron considers that you have overestimated the threat you pose.
{DRT_GERMAN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}Unacceptable, even for your promise of ongoing tributes. 
{DRT_GERMAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}You must either be a fool, or think us one! We are not about to offer you the perfect chance to strike at our heart.
{DRT_GERMAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Your invitation to enter your lands seems strange, and until we are certain it is not a trap of some sort, must decline.
{DRT_GERMAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Your people are known too well for making promises they do not keep, and we are not willing to adopt a plan of battle where we cannot rely upon who will take the field.
{DRT_GERMAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}We reject the notion that you have the intention to carry out your threat, and that you would not dismiss our agreement after you have what you have asked for.
{DRT_GERMAN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}We would appreciate these lands, but we frankly do not trust that you do not offer them without a plan to betray us and take it back.
{DRT_GERMAN_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}Your people's history is one of weakness, I do not trust your offer.
{DRT_GERMAN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}Though you may appear sincere in your offer of ongoing tribute, we lack confidence in both your ability and intention to see this through.
{DRT_GERMAN_FINISHED}.
{DRT_GERMAN_GIFT}The Great Lord Sauron hopes that you will accept this gift with the goodwill in which it is offered to your people.
{DRT_GERMAN_INFO}The Great Eye has knowledge that it would happily share with you.
{DRT_GERMAN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}Everything has a time to live and a time to die. Our alliance has reached its time to die, so let us part. 
{DRT_GERMAN_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accept my hand in marriage, forming a strong alliance between our peoples to last the test of time.
{DRT_GERMAN_PROTECTORATE}Accept that your people will be crushed by the Dark Lord unless you can forget your pride and offer yourself as a vassal of the Great Eye!
{DRT_GERMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_GERMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_GERMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_GERMAN_REJECT_BRIBE}You are ignoring the fact I have a sense of loyalty, which is both arrogant and insulting.
{DRT_GERMAN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}We are just not interested in discussing this with you... Understand?
{DRT_GERMAN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}You are not sincere about reaching an agreement. This is too inefficient a way to be spending our time, and we shall end this here.
{DRT_GERMAN_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}It is time for us to seal a serious pact through a royal marriage.
{DRT_GERMAN_SELL_VOTE}Perhaps you would want our support in the election?
{DRT_GERMAN_THREAT}Unless you can give us good reason to spare your lands and people, the Reich will take what it feels it needs by force.
{DRT_GERMAN_TRADE}Establishing trade is the ideal way for our people to begin dealing with one another.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_BRIBE}Knowing that you would deign to spend such a sum to secure my allegiance is all I need to be sure that you are the right master to serve.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Very well, you can count on our support.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_GIFT}Your well-intentioned gift is welcome, and you have our gratitude.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We look forward to the wedding, and our future together throughout the years.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}I pray that this union between us shall be prosperous.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}We are grateful to be able to count on your support.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACCESS}If you would grant our armies access through your lands, it would benefit our struggle against our enemies.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_GONDOR_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_GONDOR_ALLIANCE}Let our people enter an alliance to strengthen both of our positions. 
{DRT_GONDOR_ATTACK}Could we ask of your assistance in battle with our enemy?
{DRT_GONDOR_BRIBE}You would find yourself in a position of power and prominence should you accept this invitation to join the our number.
{DRT_GONDOR_BUY_VOTE}Perhaps we could call upon your support in the election?
{DRT_GONDOR_CEASEFIRE}Let us stop the bloodshed, and bring open hostilities to an end.
{DRT_GONDOR_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_GONDOR_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_GONDOR_COUNTER_INFO}Our people would like to share some information with you.
{DRT_GONDOR_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_GONDOR_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_ACCESS}While you can see the need to march your soldiers through our lands, we do not. Permission must be refused at this time. 
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}We do not believe an alliance would be in our best interests at this time. 
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_ATTACK}Attacking these people is not in our best interests, so we must refuse. 
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}We will not be bartering over this serious moment of ascension.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}My Lord does not share your desperate and cowardly urge to escape battle. Perhaps you now realise that you will lose this struggle?
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_DEMAND}We simply do not see how to attempt to meet these demands.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_GIFT}Our people cannot trust the nature in which this gift is intended.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_NULLIFY}We are not willing to abandon our treaty with these people simply because you would wish it to happen.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}This is too serious a union for us to consider at this moment.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_OFFER}We cannot match this offer, and must decline as a result.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}This is far too generous and we would owe you too much.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}You simply do not offer enough with this.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}Why do you think we have not surrendered yet? Maintaining our freedom is as important as maintaining our very lives.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_REGION}To give up the lands our people died to earn and defend for a pouch of coin simply would not do.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We shall not consider a royal union under any doubt or duress.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}We are not looking to buy your support like this.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_THREAT}Our people has no fear of your threats, which to be honest seem hollow.
{DRT_GONDOR_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}We cannot agree to this, even for a steady supply of coin.
{DRT_GONDOR_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Our people has no desire for your armies to study the lay of our lands.
{DRT_GONDOR_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Though that access could be useful for our people in times of war, we cannot be certain that you wouldn't change your mind once we begin to cross your lands. 
{DRT_GONDOR_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Your promise of support is the kind that is easy to make without actually having to honour it.
{DRT_GONDOR_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}We do not believe that you will stay your swords even if we meet your demands.
{DRT_GONDOR_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}Your offer of land seems most generous, but there is enough reason to doubt that you wouldn't seek to take it back from us by one means or another.
{DRT_GONDOR_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}Your people's history is one of broken promises, I do not trust your offer.
{DRT_GONDOR_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}We do not believe that you are capable of honouring such a series of tributes, even if you truly intend to.
{DRT_GONDOR_FINISHED}.
{DRT_GONDOR_GIFT}Accept this gift as an example of our goodwill. 
{DRT_GONDOR_INFO}We would wish to share our knowledge of the world with you.
{DRT_GONDOR_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}The time for our alliance's demise has come to pass. We shall both seek our own path to glory now. 
{DRT_GONDOR_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accept my hand in marriage and unite our people in an alliance to last.
{DRT_GONDOR_PROTECTORATE}Why continue to struggle against our superior forces? Become our vassal and we shall lead you to greatness under our rule.
{DRT_GONDOR_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_GONDOR_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_GONDOR_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_GONDOR_REJECT_BRIBE}My loyalty is not something that you can put a price on so simply.
{DRT_GONDOR_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}Nous ne souhaitons tout simplement pas discuter d'une telle proposition.
{DRT_GONDOR_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}Nous ne faisons pas assez de progrès ici pour suggérer qu'il y a une raison de continuer ... Ces négociations sont terminées.
{DRT_GONDOR_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}It is time for us to seal a serious pact through a royal marriage.
{DRT_GONDOR_SELL_VOTE}Peut-être voudriez-vous notre soutien lors des élections?
{DRT_GONDOR_THREAT}We can afford to spare you from our conquests, should of course you be prepared to pay tribute as such...
{DRT_GONDOR_TRADE}It would be quite profitable for both of our peoples to establish trade between us.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_BRIBE}Sachant que vous daigneriez dépenser une telle somme pour obtenir mon allégeance, je n'ai besoin que d'être sûr que vous êtes le bon maître pour servir.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Très bien, vous pouvez compter sur notre soutien.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_GIFT}Votre cadeau bien intentionné est le bienvenu et vous avez notre gratitude.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}We look forward to the wedding, and our future together throughout the years.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}I pray that this union between us shall be prosperous.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}We are grateful to be able to count on your support.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACCESS}Si vous autorisiez nos armées à accéder à vos terres, notre lutte contre nos ennemis serait bénéfique.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_QUENYA_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_QUENYA_ALLIANCE}Laissons nos peuples former une alliance pour renforcer nos deux positions.
{DRT_QUENYA_ATTACK}Pouvons-nous demander votre aide dans la bataille avec notre ennemi?
{DRT_QUENYA_BRIBE}You would find yourself in a position of power and prominence should you accept this invitation to join the our number.
{DRT_QUENYA_BUY_VOTE}Peut-être pourrions-nous faire appel à votre soutien lors des élections?
{DRT_QUENYA_CEASEFIRE}Arrêtons l'effusion de sang et mettons fin aux hostilités ouvertes.
{DRT_QUENYA_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_QUENYA_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_QUENYA_COUNTER_INFO}Notre personnel aimerait partager certaines informations avec vous.
{DRT_QUENYA_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_QUENYA_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_ACCESS}Vous pouvez voir la nécessité de faire marcher vos soldats sur nos terres, mais nous ne le faisons pas. L'autorisation doit être refusée à ce moment.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}Nous ne croyons pas qu'une alliance serait dans notre meilleur intérêt pour le moment.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_ATTACK}Attaquer ces personnes n’est pas dans notre intérêt, nous devons donc refuser.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}Nous ne négocierons pas ce grave moment d’ascension.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}Mon Seigneur ne partage pas votre désir désespéré et lâche d'échapper à la bataille. Peut-être que vous réalisez maintenant que vous allez perdre cette lutte?
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_DEMAND}Nous ne voyons tout simplement pas comment tenter de répondre à ces demandes.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_GIFT}Notre peuple ne peut pas faire confiance à la nature dans laquelle ce cadeau est destiné.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_NULLIFY}Nous ne souhaitons pas abandonner notre traité avec ces personnes simplement parce que vous souhaiteriez que cela se produise.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}C’est un syndicat trop sérieux pour que nous puissions l’envisager en ce moment.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_OFFER}Nous ne pouvons pas égaler cette offre et devons donc décliner.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}C'est beaucoup trop généreux et on vous en doit trop.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}Vous n'offrez tout simplement pas assez avec cela.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}Pourquoi pensez-vous que nous ne sommes pas encore rendus? Maintenir notre liberté est aussi important que maintenir notre vie même.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_REGION}Abandonner les terres que notre peuple est mort pour gagner et défendre pour une poche de pièces de monnaie ne ferait tout simplement pas l'affaire.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Nous ne considérerons pas l'union royale sous aucun doute ou contrainte.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}Nous ne cherchons pas à acheter votre soutien comme ça.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_THREAT}Notre peuple n'a pas peur de vos menaces, qui pour être honnête semblent vides.
{DRT_QUENYA_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}Nous ne pouvons pas accepter cela, même pour un approvisionnement régulier en pièces.
{DRT_QUENYA_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Notre peuple ne souhaite pas que vos armées étudient la configuration de nos terres.
{DRT_QUENYA_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Bien que cet accès puisse être utile à notre peuple en temps de guerre, nous ne pouvons pas être certains que vous ne changeriez pas d'avis une fois que nous aurons commencé à traverser vos terres.
{DRT_QUENYA_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Votre promesse de soutien est facile à faire sans avoir à l’honorer.
{DRT_QUENYA_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}Nous ne croyons pas que vous resterez vos épées même si nous répondons à vos demandes.
{DRT_QUENYA_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}Votre offre de terre semble très généreuse, mais il y a suffisamment de raisons de douter que vous ne cherchiez pas à nous la reprendre par l'un ou l'autre moyen.
{DRT_QUENYA_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}L’histoire de votre peuple est celle de promesses non tenues, je ne fais pas confiance à votre offre.
{DRT_QUENYA_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}Nous ne pensons pas que vous soyez capable d’honorer une telle série d’hommages, même si vous avez l’intention de le faire.
{DRT_QUENYA_FINISHED}.
{DRT_QUENYA_GIFT}Acceptez ce cadeau comme exemple de notre bonne volonté.
{DRT_QUENYA_INFO}Nous souhaiterions partager notre connaissance du monde avec vous.
{DRT_QUENYA_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}Le temps de la disparition de notre alliance est arrivé. Nous rechercherons tous les deux notre propre chemin vers la gloire maintenant.
{DRT_QUENYA_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accepter ma main dans le mariage et unir notre peuple dans une alliance pour durer.
{DRT_QUENYA_PROTECTORATE}Pourquoi continuer à lutter contre nos forces supérieures? Devenez notre vassal et nous vous conduirons à la grandeur sous notre règne.
{DRT_QUENYA_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_QUENYA_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_QUENYA_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_QUENYA_REJECT_BRIBE}Ma loyauté n’est pas une chose sur laquelle vous pouvez simplement mettre un prix.
{DRT_QUENYA_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}Nous ne souhaitons tout simplement pas discuter d'une telle proposition.
{DRT_QUENYA_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}Nous ne faisons pas assez de progrès ici pour suggérer qu'il y a une raison de continuer ... Ces négociations sont terminées.
{DRT_QUENYA_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Il est temps que nous concluions un pacte sérieux par le biais d'un mariage royal.
{DRT_QUENYA_SELL_VOTE}Peut-être voudriez-vous notre soutien lors des élections?
{DRT_QUENYA_THREAT}Nous pouvons nous permettre de vous épargner de nos conquêtes si vous êtes bien disposé à rendre hommage en tant que tel ...
{DRT_QUENYA_TRADE}Il serait tout à fait avantageux pour nos deux peuples d’établir un commerce entre nous.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_BRIBE}Votre investissement judicieux dans mes services prouve que je sers maintenant un maître plus sournois et plus reconnaissant.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Oui, vous pouvez compter sur notre soutien.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_GIFT}Votre cadeau bien intentionné est le bienvenu. Vous avez notre gratitude.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Nous attendons avec impatience le mariage et notre avenir ensemble au fil des ans.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Je prie pour que cette union entre nous soit prospère.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}Nous apprécions pouvoir compter sur votre soutien.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACCESS}Si vous autorisiez nos armées à accéder à vos terres, notre lutte contre nos ennemis serait bénéfique.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ALLIANCE}Une alliance entre notre peuple renforcerait nos deux positions.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_ATTACK}Pouvons-nous vous demander votre aide dans notre combat contre notre ennemi?
{DRT_SCOTTISH_BRIBE}Vous vous retrouveriez dans une position de pouvoir et de notoriété si vous vouliez nommer votre prix à la couronne écossaise.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_BUY_VOTE}Peut-être pourrions-nous faire appel à votre soutien lors de l'élection papale?
{DRT_SCOTTISH_CEASEFIRE}Arrêtons l'effusion de sang et mettons fin aux hostilités ouvertes.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_COUNTER_INFO}Les nains aimeraient partager certaines informations avec vous.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_ACCESS}Nos terres ne sont pas simplement une voie de communication pour les autres, nous ne pouvons pas accepter.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}Nous ne voyons pas encore le besoin d’une alliance pour le moment.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_ATTACK}Attaquer ces personnes n’est pas dans notre intérêt. Nous devons refuser.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}Nous ne négocierons pas le contrôle du Seigneur des Ténèbres de cette façon.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}Nous ne partageons pas votre lâche envie de mettre fin à notre conflit.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_DEMAND}Nous ne voyons tout simplement pas comment tenter de répondre à ces demandes.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_GIFT}Nous ne pouvons pas faire confiance à la nature dans laquelle ce cadeau est destiné.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_NULLIFY}Nous ne souhaitons pas annuler cette alliance simplement parce qu'elle sert vos objectifs.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}C’est un syndicat trop sérieux pour que nous puissions l’envisager en ce moment.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_OFFER}Nous ne pouvons pas égaler cette offre et devons donc décliner.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}C'est beaucoup trop généreux et on vous en doit trop.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}Vous n'offrez tout simplement pas assez avec cela.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}Nous, Écossais, accordons de la valeur à la liberté avant toute autre chose - Ne le suggérez plus jamais?
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_REGION}Trop de fils de notre peuple ont donné leur vie pour ces terres ... Nous ne pouvons pas les abandonner pour un tas de pièces de monnaie.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Nous ne considérerons pas l'union royale sous aucun doute ou contrainte.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}Nous ne cherchons pas à acheter votre soutien comme ça.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_THREAT}Nous sommes disposés à voir si vos menaces sont vides.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}Nous ne pouvons pas accepter cela, même pour un approvisionnement régulier en pièces.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Nous ne souhaitons pas que vos armées s'habituent à ses terres.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Bien que cet accès puisse être utile aux nains en temps de guerre, nous ne pouvons pas être certains que vous ne changeriez pas d'avis lorsque nous traverserons vos terres.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Vous supposez que nous voulons votre aide pour attaquer nos ennemis. Plus important encore, votre promesse de soutien est facile à faire sans respecter.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}Nous ne croyons pas que vous resterez vos épées même si nous répondons à vos demandes.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}Votre offre de terre semble très généreuse, mais il y a suffisamment de raisons de douter que vous ne cherchiez pas à nous la reprendre par quelque moyen que ce soit.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}L’histoire de votre peuple est celle de promesses non tenues, je ne fais pas confiance à votre offre.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}Nous ne pensons pas que vous soyez capable d’honorer une telle série d’hommages, ni que vous aviez vraiment l’intention de le faire.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_FINISHED}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_GIFT}Acceptez ce cadeau comme un signe de notre bonne volonté envers votre peuple.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_INFO}Si nous partageons notre connaissance du monde, nous en profiterons tous.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}Le temps de la fin de notre alliance doit être passé. Nous rechercherons tous les deux notre propre chemin vers la gloire maintenant.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accepter ma main dans le mariage, formant une alliance forte entre notre peuple.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_PROTECTORATE}Pourquoi continuer à vivre sous notre menace constante? Devenez notre vassal et nous vous conduirons à la grandeur sous la domination écossaise.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_REJECT_BRIBE}Notre fidélité n’est pas quelque chose que vous pouvez acheter si simplement.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}Nous ne sommes tout simplement pas intéressés par une telle proposition.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}Nous avons trop bavardé sans résultat.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Votre Altesse accepterait-elle une proposition de mariage avec la famille royale écossaise, unissant notre grand peuple dans une alliance?
{DRT_SCOTTISH_SELL_VOTE}Peut-être voudriez-vous notre soutien lors de l'élection papale?
{DRT_SCOTTISH_THREAT}Les nains peuvent accepter d'épargner vos terres si vous êtes prêt à lui rendre un hommage pour ne pas les prendre comme vous le savez si bien.
{DRT_SCOTTISH_TRADE}Établir un commerce entre nous serait bénéfique pour nous deux. Vous seriez sûrement d'accord?
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}Sachant que vous daigneriez dépenser une telle somme pour obtenir mon allégeance, je n'ai besoin que d'être sûr que vous êtes le bon maître pour servir.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Très bien, vous pouvez compter sur notre soutien.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_GIFT}Votre cadeau bien intentionné est le bienvenu et vous avez notre gratitude.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Nous attendons avec impatience le mariage et notre avenir ensemble au fil des ans.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Je prie pour que cette union entre nous soit prospère.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}Nous sommes reconnaissants de pouvoir compter sur votre soutien.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACCESS}Si vous autorisiez nos armées à accéder à vos terres, notre lutte contre nos ennemis serait bénéfique.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ALLIANCE}Laissons nos peuples former une alliance pour renforcer nos deux positions.
{DRT_SINDARIN_ATTACK}Pouvons-nous demander votre aide dans la bataille avec notre ennemi?
{DRT_SINDARIN_BRIBE}Vous vous retrouveriez dans une position de pouvoir et de notoriété si vous acceptez cette invitation à rejoindre notre numéro.
{DRT_SINDARIN_BUY_VOTE}Peut-être pourrions-nous faire appel à votre soutien lors des élections?
{DRT_SINDARIN_CEASEFIRE}Arrêtons l'effusion de sang et mettons fin aux hostilités ouvertes.
{DRT_SINDARIN_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_COUNTER_INFO}Notre personnel aimerait partager certaines informations avec vous.
{DRT_SINDARIN_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_ACCESS}Vous pouvez voir la nécessité de faire marcher vos soldats sur nos terres, mais nous ne le faisons pas. L'autorisation doit être refusée à ce moment.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}Nous ne croyons pas qu'une alliance serait dans notre meilleur intérêt pour le moment.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_ATTACK}Attaquer ces personnes n’est pas dans notre intérêt, nous devons donc refuser.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}Nous ne négocierons pas ce grave moment d’ascension.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}Mon Seigneur ne partage pas votre désir désespéré et lâche d'échapper à la bataille. Peut-être que vous réalisez maintenant que vous allez perdre cette lutte?
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_DEMAND}Nous ne voyons tout simplement pas comment tenter de répondre à ces demandes.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_GIFT}Notre peuple ne peut pas faire confiance à la nature dans laquelle ce cadeau est destiné.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}Nous ne souhaitons pas abandonner notre traité avec ces personnes simplement parce que vous souhaiteriez que cela se produise.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}C’est un syndicat trop sérieux pour que nous puissions l’envisager en ce moment.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_OFFER}Nous ne pouvons pas égaler cette offre et devons donc décliner.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}C'est beaucoup trop généreux et on vous en doit trop.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}Vous n'offrez tout simplement pas assez avec cela.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}Pourquoi pensez-vous que nous ne sommes pas encore rendus? Maintenir notre liberté est aussi important que maintenir notre vie même.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_REGION}Abandonner les terres que notre peuple est mort pour gagner et défendre pour une poche de pièces de monnaie ne ferait tout simplement pas l'affaire.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Nous ne considérerons pas l'union royale sous aucun doute ou contrainte.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}Nous ne cherchons pas à acheter votre soutien comme ça.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_THREAT}Notre peuple n'a pas peur de vos menaces, qui pour être honnête semblent vides.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}Nous ne pouvons pas accepter cela, même pour un approvisionnement régulier en pièces.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Notre peuple ne souhaite pas que vos armées étudient la configuration de nos terres.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Bien que cet accès puisse être utile à notre peuple en temps de guerre, nous ne pouvons pas être certains que vous ne changeriez pas d'avis une fois que nous aurons commencé à traverser vos terres.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Votre promesse de soutien est facile à faire sans avoir à l’honorer.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}Nous ne croyons pas que vous resterez vos épées même si nous répondons à vos demandes.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}Votre offre de terre semble très généreuse, mais il y a suffisamment de raisons de douter que vous ne cherchiez pas à nous la reprendre par l'un ou l'autre moyen.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}L’histoire de votre peuple est celle de promesses non tenues, je ne fais pas confiance à votre offre.
{DRT_SINDARIN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}Nous ne pensons pas que vous soyez capable d’honorer une telle série d’hommages, même si vous avez l’intention de le faire.
{DRT_SINDARIN_FINISHED}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_GIFT}Acceptez ce cadeau comme exemple de notre bonne volonté.
{DRT_SINDARIN_INFO}Nous souhaiterions partager notre connaissance du monde avec vous.
{DRT_SINDARIN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}Le temps de la disparition de notre alliance est arrivé. Nous rechercherons tous les deux notre propre chemin vers la gloire maintenant.
{DRT_SINDARIN_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accepter ma main dans le mariage et unir notre peuple dans une alliance pour durer.
{DRT_SINDARIN_PROTECTORATE}Pourquoi continuer à lutter contre nos forces supérieures? Devenez notre vassal et nous vous conduirons à la grandeur sous notre règne.
{DRT_SINDARIN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_SINDARIN_REJECT_BRIBE}Ma loyauté n’est pas une chose sur laquelle vous pouvez simplement mettre un prix.
{DRT_SINDARIN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}Nous ne souhaitons tout simplement pas discuter d'une telle proposition.
{DRT_SINDARIN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}Nous ne faisons pas assez de progrès ici pour suggérer qu'il y a une raison de continuer ... Ces négociations sont terminées.
{DRT_SINDARIN_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Il est temps que nous concluions un pacte sérieux par le biais d'un mariage royal.
{DRT_SINDARIN_SELL_VOTE}Peut-être voudriez-vous notre soutien lors des élections?
{DRT_SINDARIN_THREAT}Nous pouvons nous permettre de vous épargner de nos conquêtes si vous êtes bien disposé à rendre hommage en tant que tel ...
{DRT_SINDARIN_TRADE}Il serait tout à fait avantageux pour nos deux peuples d’établir un commerce entre nous.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}Il est clair que votre confiance en mes capacités est plus sérieuse que celle de mon ancien maître.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_BUY_VOTE}Oui, vous pouvez compter sur notre soutien.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_GIFT}Votre cadeau est le bienvenu et vous avez notre gratitude.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Nous attendons avec impatience le mariage et notre avenir ensemble au fil des ans.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_RECOMMUNICATION}Le Seigneur des Ténèbres accepte votre chef de retour dans l'ombre.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}J'espère sincèrement que cette union entre nous sera la meilleure pour nous tous.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCEPT_SELL_VOTE}Si vous nous soutenez comme vous le dites, nous ne l'oublierons pas.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACCESS}Si vous autorisiez nos armées à accéder à vos terres, notre lutte contre nos ennemis serait bénéfique.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLINE}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ALLIANCE}Rejoignez-nous dans une alliance pour renforcer nos chances de réaliser nos ambitions ensemble, en tant que frères d'armes.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_ATTACK}Aidez-nous à vaincre notre ennemi et nous vous en serons extrêmement reconnaissants.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_BRIBE}Acceptez plus de pouvoir et de respect que ce à quoi vous êtes habitués en rejoignant notre cause. Il suffit de nommer votre prix.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_BUY_VOTE}Peut-être pourrions-nous faire appel à votre soutien lors de l'élection papale?
{DRT_UNKNOWN_CEASEFIRE}Le sang versé entre nous est devenu sans signification, mettons fin à cette guerre aujourd'hui.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_COUNTER_BRIBE}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_COUNTER_DEMAND}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_COUNTER_INFO}Nous espérons que vous trouverez cette information utile.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_COUNTER_OFFER}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_ACCESS}Nous ne sommes actuellement pas disposés à accepter toute proposition impliquant un passage militaire.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}Nous ne pensons pas qu'il soit nécessaire de former une alliance avec vous.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_ATTACK}Nous ne sommes pas disposés à attaquer comme vous le demandez. Être en guerre avec ces gens peut être votre priorité, mais ce n'est pas la nôtre.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_BUY_VOTE}Nous ne négocierons pas le contrôle du Seigneur des Ténèbres de cette façon.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}Vous êtes le seul à vouloir trouver une solution pacifique à cette guerre.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_DEMAND}Vous demandez quelque chose que nous ne ferons tout simplement pas.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_GIFT}Ne comprenant pas pourquoi vous nous offriez ce cadeau, nous devons refuser.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}Pour nous, il n'y a aucune raison valable de mettre fin à l'alliance entre nos deux peuples.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}C’est un syndicat trop sérieux pour que nous puissions l’envisager en ce moment.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_OFFER}Ce n'est pas une offre que nous pouvons égaler maintenant, et doit décliner.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}C’est beaucoup trop généreux, notre peuple vous doit trop.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}Vous n'offrez tout simplement pas assez avec cela.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}L'idée de devenir vos serviteurs est sans appel. Cela n'arrivera pas.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_RECOMMUNICATION}Compte tenu de l'histoire de votre chef, le Seigneur des Ténèbres n'est pas encore convaincu de la nécessité de la réconciliation.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_REGION}Nos générations précédentes ont donné leur sang et leur vie pour avoir le droit d'appeler ces terres les leurs. Nous ne déshonorerons donc pas leurs actes en vendant ce pour quoi elles se sont battues.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}C'est un trop grand pacte pour que nous puissions l'accepter.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_SELL_VOTE}Nous préférerions laisser cela à la volonté de Dieu.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_THREAT}Vos menaces sont vides et nous risquerons votre colère supposée.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}Même les paiements honorés ne nous verraient pas accepter votre proposition.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}Qui peut dire que vous ne cherchez pas un moyen de trouver un pillage plus facile en abaissant nos défenses frontalières? Ce n'est pas à vous de le faire.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}Vous pouvez laisser nos forces sur vos terres, mais les laisseriez-vous partir? Nous sommes trop incertains ici.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}Puisque nous ne pouvons pas être sûrs que vous nous aideriez comme vous le dites, nous ne pouvons accepter cet accord.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}Qu'est-ce qui veut dire que vous n'essayez pas simplement de nous piller avant de frapper comme prévu?
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}Il n'y a aucune raison de croire que vous avez de vraies intentions de laisser cette terre aller sans un plan pour la récupérer ... Pas avec votre réputation.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DISHONEST_SELL_VOTE}L’histoire de votre peuple est celle de promesses non tenues, nous ne pouvons faire confiance à votre offre.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}La question de votre volonté et de votre capacité d'honorer votre offre est trop grande.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_FINISHED}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_GIFT}Veuillez accepter ce cadeau comme symbole de notre respect pour votre peuple et votre cause.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_INFO}Le partage des connaissances profite à tous, n'êtes-vous pas d'accord?
{DRT_UNKNOWN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}Nous n'avons plus besoin de travailler ensemble dans notre quête de gloire. Nous réalisons que nous ne le trouverons pas avec vous.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_OFFER_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Accepteras-tu ma main dans le mariage, formant une alliance solide entre nos nobles peuples?
{DRT_UNKNOWN_PROTECTORATE}Vous savez que vous luttez en vain contre une défaite inévitable? Évitez cela en devenant notre vassal et votre peuple prospérera sous notre règne.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_RECOMMUNICATION}La proposition de réconcilier avec sa sainteté est sûrement une proposition que vous et votre peuple ne pouvez pas vous permettre de rejeter.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_REJECT_BRIBE}Pourquoi ne devrais-je pas être offensé de penser que ma loyauté est à vendre?
{DRT_UNKNOWN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}C'est quelque chose dont nous ne sommes tout simplement pas intéressés à discuter.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}Il semble que nous ne résolvions pas beaucoup ici maintenant, et j’ai d’autres tâches à régler.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_REQUEST_MARRIAGE_ALLIANCE}Il est temps que nous concluions un pacte sérieux par le biais d'un mariage royal.
{DRT_UNKNOWN_SELL_VOTE}Peut-être voudriez-vous notre soutien lors de l'élection papale?
{DRT_UNKNOWN_THREAT}Plutôt que de simplement prendre vos terres et de les piller, vous êtes peut-être assez sage pour nous offrir un tribut afin que nous puissions diriger notre conquête ailleurs?
{DRT_UNKNOWN_TRADE}Le commerce est la première étape vers un bénéfice mutuel, prenons-le ensemble.
{DT_ALLIED_TURNS}Alliés pour% d tours
{DT_ALLIED_TURN}Alliés pour% d tour
{DT_ASSISTANCE_PROVIDED_AGAINST}Assistance fournie contre
{DT_ASSISTANCE_REQUESTED_AGAINST}Assistance demandée contre
{DT_AT_WAR_TURNS}En guerre pour% d tours
{DT_AT_WAR_TURN}En guerre pour% d Turn
{DT_BEHAVIOUR}Détails et comportement
{DT_DEMEANOUR}Comportement:
{DT_DIPLOMACY_INSTRUCTIONS}Sélectionnez les éléments énumérés à gauche de ce parchemin pour créer une proposition diplomatique.
{DT_MILITARY_ACCESS_GIVEN}Accès militaire donné
{DT_MILITARY_ACCESS_RECEIVED}Accès militaire reçu
{DT_NEUTRAL_TURNS}Neutre pour% d tours
{DT_NEUTRAL_TURN}Neutre pour% d tour
{DT_NO_TREATIES}Aucun
{DT_POWER}Puissance:
{DT_POWER_0}Impuissant
{DT_POWER_1}Pathétique
{DT_POWER_2}Très faible
{DT_POWER_3}Faible
{DT_POWER_4}Modeste
{DT_POWER_5}Moyenne
{DT_POWER_6}Capable
{DT_POWER_7}Respectable
{DT_POWER_8}Fort
{DT_POWER_9}Très fort
{DT_POWER_10}Suprême
{DT_PRIORITIES}Les priorités:
{DT_PRIORITY_MILITARY}Militaire
{DT_PRIORITY_PEACE}Paix
{DT_PRIORITY_TRADE}Commerce
{DT_PRIORITY_WAR}Guerre
{DT_PROPOSAL_BALANCE}Solde de la proposition:
{DT_PROTECTOR}Protecteur
{DT_RELATIONS}Rapports:
{DT_RELATIONS_0}Épouvantable
{DT_RELATIONS_1}Terrible
{DT_RELATIONS_2}Très pauvre
{DT_RELATIONS_3}Pauvre
{DT_RELATIONS_4}Comme ci comme ça
{DT_RELATIONS_5}Raisonnable
{DT_RELATIONS_6}Amiable
{DT_RELATIONS_7}Bien
{DT_RELATIONS_8}Très bon
{DT_RELATIONS_9}Exceptionnel
{DT_RELATIONS_10}Parfait
{DT_REPUTATION}Réputation:
{DT_REPUTATION_0}Méprisable
{DT_REPUTATION_1}Trompeur
{DT_REPUTATION_2}Très indigne de confiance
{DT_REPUTATION_3}Indigne de confiance
{DT_REPUTATION_4}Douteux
{DT_REPUTATION_5}Mixte
{DT_REPUTATION_6}Fiable
{DT_REPUTATION_7}Très fiable
{DT_REPUTATION_8}Digne de confiance
{DT_REPUTATION_9}Très digne de confiance
{DT_REPUTATION_10}Immaculé
{DT_STANCES_ALLIES}Alliés
{DT_STANCES_ENEMIES}Ennemis:
{DT_STANCES_NO_ALLIES}Aucun
{DT_STANCES_NO_ENEMIES}Aucun
{DT_STANCES}Alliés et Ennemis
{DT_TRADE_RIGHTS_GRANTED}Droits commerciaux accordés
{DT_TREATIES}Traités actuels:
{DT_TRIBUTE_PAYED}Tribut Payé (% d Pièces):
{DT_TRIBUTE_RECEIVED}Hommage reçu (% d Coins):
{DT_UNKNOWN_PRIORITIES}Inconnu
{DT_WEALTH}Richesse:
{DT_WEALTH_0}Faillite
{DT_WEALTH_1}Maigre
{DT_WEALTH_2}Très pauvre
{DT_WEALTH_3}Pauvre
{DT_WEALTH_4}Modeste
{DT_WEALTH_5}Raisonnable
{DT_WEALTH_6}Bien nanti
{DT_WEALTH_7}Riches
{DT_WEALTH_8}Très riche
{DT_WEALTH_9}Extrême
{DT_WEALTH_10}Sans bornes